TV를 볼 때에는 방을 밝게 하고 TV에서 떨어져서 봅시다.
When you're watching television, be sure to keep your room bright and keep distance from the TV!
강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
다들 오래 기다렸다.
I've been waiting for you guys.
소개하지. 텐료 잇키 군과...
Let me introduce them. Tenryo Ikki and...
메타비 씨군요? 박사님.
And Metabee, I see, Professor?
실례합니다!
Excuse us!
여긴 잇키 군의 친구인
This is Ikki's friend.
아, 유즈루에요.
I'm Yuzuru.
잇키 군과 메타비 군이 온 건 데스 메다로트의 성능에 대한 여러 정보를 얻기 위해서야.
Ikki and Metabee are here to tell us about the performances and various information about Death Medarots.
특히 블로소메일에 대해서.
Especially about Blossomail.
유, 유즈루, 저거 봤어?
Y- Yuzuru, did you see that?
어, 저 방 구석의 케이스?
You mean the case over there?
아니! 박사님, 저 책상 위에 것들은요?
Nope! Professor, what about the things on that table?
저건 협력해 주는 자네들을 위한 보상이야. 원하는 만큼 먹어라.
It's a reward for helping us out. Eat as much as you want.
아싸! 가자, 유즈루!
Yay! Let's go, Yuzuru!
아, 거 참...
Oh dear...
잇키 군, 친구들 더 데리고 올 것 아니었나?
Ikki, weren't you taking more friends with you?
얘들은 변덕쟁이니까 약속 안 지켰나 보죠!
They're moody, so they must've changed their decision!
나한텐 뭔 보상 없어?
Don't I get any reward?
돌아가는 길에 나에 씨 가게에서 오일 블루에 넣어 줄게!
I'll let you in to Oil Blue at Ms. Nae's store on the way back!
정말!?
Really!?
바로 메타비 군의 기억 영상을 재생해서 블로소메일과의 전투를 보도록 하지.
We're going to play Metabee's memory video, and take a look at the battle against Blossomail right away.
하세요, 하세요!
Go ahead, do it!
네가 답장하지 마라.
Don't you respond instead of me.
훔쳐진 메타비
Stolen Metabee
(en: Metabee's Out of Body Experience)
잇키 놈, 먼저 간 것 같아요.
It seems that Ikki went ahead of us.
대지각이에요.
We're so late!
그런 줄 알아라. 레이디의 외출에는 뭔가 준비할 시간이 필요해.
Deal with it. Ladies need time to prepare when going out.
안됐네요. 블로소메일의 체험담을 이야기하는 것만으로 개발중인 신형 메다로트를 볼 수 있었을 텐데!
Too bad. It was a rare chance to take a look at new Medarots in development only by talking about Blossomail!
먹을 것도 준다고 했었는데!
He told us they're going to give us food, too!
투덜대지 마! 지금이라도 늦지 않아! 가자, 메다로트 연구소에!
Don't grumble! We're not late yet! Let's go to the Medarot Research Facility!
메다로트 연구소?
Medarot Research Facility?
긴카이! 이런 곳에서 뭐 하는 거야!?
Ginkai! What are you doing here?!
지하철 홈에서 누워서 자다니, 초등학교 4학년이 할 일은 아닌데요.
Lying down in a subway platform isn't something that elementary school 4th grader would do!
시꺼! 그보다도 메다로트 연구소가 이러쿵저러쿵 그랬지?
Shaddup! Anyway, you said something about Medarot Research Facility, right?
너하고는 관계 없어!
It has nothing to do with you!
죄송합니다죄송합니다죄송합니다
I'm sorryI'm sorryI'm sorry
자, 잠깐, 긴카이. 메다로트 연구소에 흥미라도 있냐?
Oh, wait, Ginkai. Are you interested in Medarot Research Facility in any way?
어, 뭐, 코쿠류가 메다로트 사의 신형이 신경쓰이나 봐.
Well, I think that Kokuryu is minding about Medarot Company's new model.
대단한 게 2대나 만들어지고 있는 것 같아서.
It seems that two interesting things are in development.
음, 코쿠류한테 바칠 이야기라도 찾고 있냐?
Oh, are you looking for a story to offer to Kokuryu?
두, 두목?
B- boss?
OK, 따라와.
OK. Follow us.
그 대신, 내 페퍼캣도 메다체인지 할 수 있도록 코쿠류한테 말해주지 않겠냐? 그게 조건이야.
Instead, tell Kokuryu to let my Peppercat be able to perform Medachange. That's the condition.
좋아, 알겠어. 부탁해 둘게.
Sure, I will. I'll tell him.
좋아. 교섭 성립. 가자.
Great. Negotiation now in effect. Let's go.
네에...
Yes...
머신건으로도 리볼버로도 대미지 없음.
Neither Machine Gun nor Revolver has dealt damage.
노멀 모드로 레크리스 모드를 상회하는 속도.
Normal Mode is faster than Reckless Mode.
다음 데이터를 봐 봅시다.
Let's take a look at the next data.
아, 이거. 메타비가 세게 치여서 날라가던 때에요.
Oh, this. Metabee was hit so hard and he flew.
메타비에게 가해진 힘을 자세히 보자.
Let's have a closer look to the power applied to Metabee.
이게 대체 무슨 힘이야. 구형이라면 아주 산산조각 났겠어.
What kind of power is this? The old model would already have been scattered.
위험해. 전투 능력도 레벨이 너무 높아.
This is bad. The combat capacity is too high.
분명 데스 메다로트는 프로그램 용량의 100%를 전투 능력으로 할당하고 있는 것 같구나. 그런 건 아이들에게 도움이 안 돼!
It seems that Death Medarot is allocating 100% of its program for combat capacity. That doesn't help children!
데스 메다로트는 폭력의 괴물이야. 가만 둘 수 없어!
Death Medarot is a monster of violence. We cannot let it be!
우리 메다로트에게는 감정이 있어. 즉, 마스터인 아이들과 메다로트는 온 마음을 담은 커뮤니케이션이 가능해.
Our Medarots have emotions. It means that they can communicate with all their hearts with their masters, the kids.
그게 우리 이상의 메다로트다.
That's the ideal Medarot of us.
메타비 군은 그 최고의 장난감이라 생각해.
I think Metabee is the best toy of that kind ever.
말 잘 하시네!
Well said!
그렇지만 혹시 블로소메일과 같은 강한 놈이 덤벼들면, 우리 메다로트는 계속 지게 되는 게...
But if something as strong as Blossomail comes to attack, then our Medarot will continue to lose...
이번에는 안 져요!
We won't lose this time!
아, 미안미안. 그래도 메타비 군이 무사했던 건 블로소메일의 배터리가 다 떨어져서잖아?
Ah, I'm sorry. But wasn't Metabee safe only because Blossomail's battery went out.
아, 그건...
Well, for that...
분명 그렇지. 그리고 아이들은 강한 것에 끌리는 것도 확실하지.
That's for sure. Also, children are inclined to strong things.
그래서 너희들에게 소개하고 싶은 게 이거야.
That's why I'd like to introduce you children this.
KBT형 아크비틀 대시
KBT Type Arcbeetle Dash
-강해 보여...
-아크비틀...
-Looks strong...
-Arcbeetle...
아크비틀 대시! KBT 신형 메다로트지. 그리고...
Arcbeetle Dash! It's a new KBT type Medarot. And...
티렐비틀.  KWG 신형이야.
Tyrelbeetle. It's a new KWG type.
KWG형 티렐비틀
KWG Type Tyrelbeetle
강해. 그러면서도 다른 메다로트와 다름없이 마음이 있어.
It's strong. It also has mind, like other Medarots.
메타비보다 3배는 비쌀 거 같아.
It looks 3 times more expensive than Metabee.
들린다, 잇키.
I heard that, Ikki.
어떠냐, 이걸로 테스트 필드에서 놀아 볼래?
Wouldn't you want to play at the test field using these?
어? 할래요, 할래요!
I will, I will!
유즈루 군은 어떠니?
Yuzuru, what about you?
자네 어디서 만난 적 없나?
Say, don't I know you?
허, 거 참...
Er, oh dear...
기쁘지, 유즈루! 풋내기 메다로터가 이렇게 강해 보이는 메다로트를 조작할 기회라니!
Aren't you happy, Yuzuru?! It's a rare chance for a novice Medarotter like you to control a strong Medarot!
봐도 봐도 대단해요, 박사님! 대 데스 메다로트 용도의 메다로트를 곧이라도 완성할 거 같다니!
You're awesome as always, professor! You're already almost done with developing a Anti Death Medarot Medarot?
아니, 이걸 만든 건 내가 아니다.
No, it's not me who made these.
어?
Huh?
그 사내는 더는 여기엔 없다.
That guy is not here anymore.
명퇴?
Fired?
관두고 말았지.
He resigned.
그는 메다로트 개발에 우수한 재능과 열의를 가지고 있었지만...
He had an excellent talent and enthusiasm for Medarot developments, but...
제 생각의 어디가 잘못되었다는 말씀이십니까?
What about my thought is wrong?
궁극의 배틀 로봇을 만드는 것, 그것이야말로 우리의 목적일 터입니다!
Making the ultimate battle robot must be our ultimate objective!
아니다! 우리가 이루고자 하는 것은 로보틀을 통해 아이들과 함께 기뻐하고
No! What we want for them is being happy with children through Robattles,
이야기로 우정을 깊게 하고 성장해 가는 것. 그런 메다로트다.
deepen the friendship through conversation, and growing up. Medarots are supposed to be like that.
왜 자네같은 우수한 기술자가 그걸 깨닫지 못하냐!
Why can't you understand that, when you're a brilliant technician!?
그건 가짜입니다! 아이들이 진짜로 원하고 있는 것은 누구보다도 강한 메다로트입니다.
That is not true! What children truly want is the strongest Medarots.
어떤 적이라도 단숨에 파괴하는 그런 강한 메다로트입니다.
Especially, Medarots that can destroy any enemies in a blink of a eye.
마이즈루 군...
Maizuru...
지금 뭘 하고 있을지.
I wonder what he's doing now.
건물 엄청 크다. 어이.
What a big building. Anyway.
네, 메다로트 연구소입니다.
Welcome to Medarot Research Facility.
거기 있는 텐료 잇키 부탁드립니다.
Please call Tenryo Ikki in there.
잠시 기다려 주세요.
Please wait.
야, 기다렸지?
Hey, I bet you've been waiting!
키쿠히메, 너희 이제야 왔냐?
Kikuhime, you're very late!
미안.
Sorry.
뭐, 됐어. 재밌는 거 있으니까 들어와!
Well, that's fine. Come in! You want to see this!
문을 열겠습니다.
We'll open the door.
잘 됐네, 긴카이.
It worked well, Ginkai.
메달 떨어뜨리지 마라, 잇키.
Don't drop the Medal, Ikki.
알아. 이건 메타비 그 자체니까!
I know. This is the whole of you, Metabee!
그러고 보니, 키쿠히메 얘들 늦네.
Anyway, Kikuhime and others are late.
나와 메타비의 멋진 모습을 놓치겠어!
They're going to miss out the cool look of Metabee and me!
좋아!
Here!
어때, 메타비. 움직여 봐.
How does it feel, Metabee? Try moving!
안 움직여져.
I can't move.
뭐?!
What?!
잇키, 등 밀어 줘.
Ikki, push my back.
아, 알았어!
S- sure!
-더 강하게!
-좋아!
-Stronger!
-Alright!
움직였다!
I can move now!
넘어졌네.
That was so sudden.
어, 뭐라 했어?
Hey, did you say anything?
갑자기 뒤돌아보지 마!
Don't turn around so suddenly!
그건... 미안!
Well... sorry!
대단해...
So awesome...
대단해!
Awesome!
여긴 메다로트의 전투 능력을 시험하는 웨스턴 존이야.
This is Western Zone, where we test Medarot's combat capabilities.
마을의 불량배 역으로 숨어 있는 옐로 터틀을 격파해 나가면서 무사히 시계탑에 닿으면 게임 종료.
If you manage to reach the clock tower, crushing Yellow Turtles, bully's role, on the way, then you win the game.
그러나 선량한 시민 역의 메다메이드를 잘못 공격하면 게임 오버야.
But if you attack any Medamaid, good citizen's role, then it's game over.
유즈루, 먼저 해 볼래?
Yuzuru, do you want to try first?
어, 네. 돈도구, 가자. 티렐비틀 출발!
Er, sure, Dondogu, let's do this. Tyrelbeetle, go for it!
접근해!
Approach!
오른쪽 전방 45도로 점프!
Jump 45 degrees to right from front!
강해. 돈도구의 메달으로 이런 힘이.
Strong. Power this strong from Dondogu's Medal?
레클리스 모드.
Reckless Mode.
전진!
Forward!
노멀 모드!
Normal Mode!
무섭게 뛰어난 기동력이군. 도쿠스 이상일 지도 모르겠다.
What a superior mobility. Maybe it might be above that of Dorcus.
정말 대단해!
Fantastic!
잘 되고 있습니다.
It's going well.
티렐은 조종하기 어려울 텐데, 잘 하네, 유즈루 군.
Tyrel is supposed to be difficult to control, but you're pretty good, Yuzuru.
우, 우연이에요.
I- it was just a luck.
적, 적!
Enemy! Enemy!
회피, 회피!
Evade! Evade!
티, 티렐비틀, 아, 그게, 어...
T- Tyrelbeetle, er, well, um...
테스트 종료.
Test end.
데이터 수신 OK.
Data received successfully.
신경쓰지 마라, 유즈루 군. 티렐은 곧 잘 움직이게 될 거야.
Don't worry, Yuzuru. Tyrel will be more maneuverable soon.
너, 실은 강한 거 아냐?
Hey, aren't you actually good at this?
설마, 거 참...
Probably not, oh dear...
그치! 그래도 잘 했어!
I knew it! Still, you were pretty good!
드디어 우리 차례야!
It's our turn now!
싫어싫어.
Nope, no way.
지금 와서!
What, now?!
이렇게 무거운 파트로는 절대 싫어! 원래 파트로 싸우게 해 줘!
I'll never do this with parts this heavy! Let me fight with my own parts!
그러면 테스트가 안 되잖아?
Then there's no purpose in testing!
시꺼!
Shut up!
두, 두목, 저거.
B- boss, look at that.
메타비잖아.
Isn't that Metabee?
모습이 이상한데...
He doesn't look right.
설마 메달이 빠져 있는 게?
Maybe his Medal is not there!
그러니까, 이건 나하고 궁합이 안 맞아!
You see, this isn't really compatible with me!
조금만 참아!
Have patience for a moment!
메타비는 신제품 안에 있군!
Metabee's inside the new product!
유니트리스 전송!
Transfer Unitrix!
이, 이런 곳에서 뭘 하려는 거야?!
W- what are you trying to do here?!
레클리스 모드!
Reckless Mode!
유니트리스가 보는 영상을 코쿠류에게 보낼 거야.
I'm going to let Kokuryu see what Unitrix sees.
이걸로 또 내 특권이 많아지는 거지!
This will grant me even more privileges!
긴카이 님의 통신입니다.
Ginkai is requesting communication.
보여 줘.
Allow.
왠일로 공훈을 세웠구나, 긴카이.
That's a rare achievement from you, Ginkai.
Medarot Damashii - Subtitles by Subdiver
잇키, 무거워서 살아있는 오뚝이가 된 것 같아!
Ikki, I feel so heavy that I feel like a living tumbler!
기대된다, 기대!
This is gonna be exciting!
있다! 스캐터 발사!
It's there! Fire Scatter!
그려!
Sure!
한 방에!
One shot and...!
대단해. 메다로트가 아닌 것 같아.
It's terrific. As if he's not a Medarot anymore...
오른쪽 후방의 건물이야! 이번엔 스캐터를 써 봐!
Now try using Sprinkle to the building at your back right!
그려!
Sure!
내일은 내일의...
Tomorrow will be...
아니, 적이 아니야! 공격 중지!
No, it's not an enemy! Stop attacking!
어?
Wha?
아, 잠깐!
Er, sorry!
미안, 메타비.
Sorry, Metabee.
갑자기 지시 취소하지 마! 몸이 생각대로 안 움직여.
Don't take back the order so suddenly! I can't move my body so freely.
적이야! 회피! 문으로 뛰어들어!
Enemy ahead! Evade! Jump into the door!
그리여!
Right!
어떠냐!
How's that?!
잇키! 큰일났어!
Ikki! I'm in pinch!
이제 어째, 적은 6대고. 젠장!
What should I do? There are 6 enemies! Damn!
거기까지. 테스트 종료.
That's good enough. Finish testing.
어? 벌써 종료해요?
What? Are we done already?
쳇, 그러니까 내가 싫다고 했잖아! 원래 쓰던 파트라면 이런 얘들한테 질 리가 없는데!
Tch, that's why I told you I don't want to! I cannot possibly have lost to these guys with my own parts!
음, 아크대시와 메타비 군의 메달 궁합은 완벽해야 했을 텐데, 아무래도 고성능이 된 운동 능력 적응에 시간이 걸리는 듯 하구나.
Hm. Arcdash and Metabee's Medals should be perfectly compatible, but it seems that it takes time to get used to.
난 이런 것에 적응하고 싶지 않아!
I don't want to get used to such thing!
흥! 별 거 아니군. 어차피 메다로트야!
Hmph! It's nothing. It's just a Medarot after all!
좋아, 니들, 이 틈에 메타비의 동체를 옮겨!
Alright, you guys! Take this moment to take Metabee's body to somewhere else!
어?
Huh?
페퍼캣의 변형 파츠를 포기하는 거야?
Are you giving up with Peppercat's transforming parts?
어쩔 수 없지.
Oh well.
들켰어요!
We've been found!
같이 달아나야지!
We have to run together!
서둘러! 내가 꾈 테니까!
Hurry up! I'll keep them busy!
-알았어!
-정말이에요?
-Got it!
-Are you sure about this?!
조잘조잘대지 마!
Don't complain!
무슨 일인가?
What's going on?
연구소 안에 침입자가 침입한 것 같습니다.
It seems that an invader is in the research facility.
유니트리스!
Unitrix!
Ciao!
실례한다.
Excuse me.
긴카이! 왜 네가 여기 있어!
Ginkai! Why are you here?!
스파이하러 왔지. 신형 메다로트 말야.
I'm here to spy the new type Medarot.
스파이 주제에 다 털어놓냐?
What kind of spy spits that out?
저기 있다!
He's there!
잠깐. 좋은 기회야. 데스 메다로트와 아크대시의 전투를 볼 수 있잖나.
Wait, it's a good chance to check out the battle between a Death Medarot and Arcdash.
잇키, 어서 원래대로 되돌려.
Ikki, return me back into my own body.
알았어!
Right!
유니트리스, 뛰어 쳐박아!
Unitrix, jump and dive into him!
로보틀은 시작했어! 파트 교환은 규칙 위반이야.
The Robattle has begun! Exchanging parts is a violation of rules!
이게! 규칙 안 지키는 데스 메다로터가 규칙을 말하냐!
How dare you talk rules, when you're a Death Medarotter without rules?!
어? 아, 그럼, 파트 교환 할래여?
Oh? Ah, then, will you exchange parts?
메타비, 아크대시 그대로 싸워 봐!
Metabee, let's fight him as Arcdash!
좋아! 이 승부, 받아서 이겨주겠어!
Alright! Let me accept this match and win!
걸려들었군. 지금 메타비 파트를 전송하면 곤란하지.
I got you. I can't let you transfer Metabee's parts right now.
-탈출 성공.
-그래도 코쿠류에게 가져다 주는 도중에 전송되고 말 거에요.
-Escape successful.
-But it'll be transferred on the way to Kokuryu!
야, 봐봐!
Hey, look at that!
이 차에 타세요.
Ride into this car.
당신, 코쿠류네 하인!
Aren't you Kokuryu's servant?
코쿠류 도련님의 지령으로 옮겨 드리러 왔습니다.
I'm here to move you guys under Kokuryu's orders.
자, 서두르세요.
Hurry.
아, 알았어!
R- right!
해 보자!
Let's do this!
약하군, 약해! 천천히 시간 끌어 주겠어!
How weak of him! Let me drag this on for a while!
이게! 이게!
H- how dare you!
촐랑대긴, 젠장!
How annoying! Damn!
움직이는 것만 해도 아주 힘들어 보이는군!
You look like you're having trouble with moving!
좋아! 작전 변경이야! 놈을 가두어 주겠어!
This calls for a change of strategy! I will shut him in!
꽤 하는군!
You!
메타비! 저기 골목길에 놈을 몰아넣어!
Metabee! Push him into that lane!
알았어!
Got it!
잇키! 막장이야!
Ikki! It's a dead end!
진정하고 방향을 바꿔!
Calm down and face the other way!
뿔이 걸려서 안 돼!
I can't! My horn is getting in way!
쏴, 쏴!
Fire, fire!
이제 어째, 잇키!
What should I do, Ikki?!
이런 공격에 이 정도의 대미지. 메타비의 장갑하고는 비교도 안 되게 강해!
This incoming damage from that attack. It is far durable than Metabee's armors!
그럼...
Well then...
후진해, 메타비!
Walk backward, Metabee!
어!
Right!
그래!
It's working!
버텨 줘!
Please endure!
벌써 끝이냐? 유니트리스, 공격 중지!
Is it over already? Unitrix, stop attacking!
왜 그럴까, 귀염둥이 메타비는 잘 시간이니?
I wonder what's wrong! Is it time for you to take a nap, Metabee?
누, 누굴 바보로 알고! 용서 못 해!
A- are you making a fool of me?! Unforgivable!
지금이야! 메타비, 백점프!
Now! Metabee, do back jump!
좋아!
Right!
스캐터, 발사!
Fire Scatter!
쳐먹어라!
Take this!
-괜찮군.
-대단한 콤비야.
-Pretty good.
-What an excellent duo!
역시 텐료 잇키는 천재구나. 이 정도로 짧은 시간에 아크대시의 특성을 살리고 쓰다니.
Tenryo Ikki, you are definitely a genius. You made the best use of Arcdash in a very short time.
어디 꼴 좋다!
Now that's what I'd like to see!
자는 건 유니트리스였네, 긴카이!
Your Unitrix is the one to take a nap, Ginkai, after all!
-젠장!
-자, 얘야, 따라와라.
-Damn!
-Now, kiddo, follow us.
어쨌든 원래 나로 되돌려 줘, 잇키.
Anyway, put me back into my own body, Ikki.
어, 그래!
Yeah, right!
왜 그러니.
What's wrong?
없어!
It's not there!
내 동체가 없어!
My body isn't there!
뭐라고!?
What did you say!?
파트 전송!
Transfer parts!
어, 어디 가버린 거야?!
W- where did it go?!
결국 못 찾았어.
I couldn't find it.
연구소 사람들이 꼭 찾아줄 거에요.
The people at the research facility will find it for you!
다음은 음양 마을, 음양 마을 역...
Next station is Ginjou village, Ginjou village...
그건... 나에 씨의 애정으로 관리받은 소중한 파트였는데.
Those were my precious parts that Ms. Nae did maintenance job with love.
그래.
Yeah.
어, 저거!
Hey, look at that!
내 몸!
My body!
아니아니!?
Wha- what?!
니들 짓이었냐!
Was it you guys?!
야!
Hey!
잇키! 전송해서 되찾아 줘!
Ikki! Transfer those and take them back!
그래!
Right!
전송은 안 될걸. 메타비의 동체는 전자파 차단 망으로 묶여 있으니까.
You can't transfer. Metabee's body is kept in electricity isolation net.
-더러워!
-돌려줘!
-How dirty!
-Give it back!
좋아. 우리를 쓰러트릴 경우의 이야기지만 말이야.
Sure. Only if you take us down, that is.
언제나처럼 억지부리는 놈들이군!
You guys always play dirty!
-메타비!
-좋아, 해 주겠어!
-Metabee!
-Alright, I will do this!
-가, 엑스사이즈.
-유니트리스, 출격!
-Go, Excise.
-Unitrix, move out!
적이 두 대든, 아크대시의 파트를 쓰고 있든, 메타비와 나라면 반드시 이겨!
Whether there are two enemies, whether with Arcdash's parts, Metabee and I will win at last!
왠지 우리가 하는 게...
I don't feel right about what we're doing...
지금와서 뭔 소리야?
What are you saying now?
어서 해치우자.
Let's get rid of him right now.
맡겨 두셔.
Leave it to me.
놈들 어디 갔어?
Where did they go?
조심해. 전방의 점검 차량 위야!
Be careful. They're on the top of the maintenance vehicle in front of you!
-긴카이.
-좋아.
-Ginkai?
-Right.
쏠게, 잇키!
I'm opening fire, Ikki!
잠깐! 안돼!
Wait! No!
먹어라!
Take this!
저런!
Darn!
차지 중?
Charging?
-작전대로 하자.
-좋아.
-Follow the strategy.
-Sure.
뭐야, 이게!
What are you doing!?
놔!
Unhand me!
던져내!
Throw them away!
안돼! 팔이 내 말을 안 들어!
I can't! My arms are not responding!
그만해! 전차야!
Stop! Train incoming!
이거 놓으라니까!
Get off me!
이대로라면 우리 것도 같이 부딪혀버릴 거야!
Our machines will crash too, in this rate!
그게 뭐? 부서지면 또 새로운 걸 가져올 테니까 걱정 안 해도 돼.
No big deal. I'll take new ones if they break, so don't worry.
정말?
You serious?
잇키, 이제 틀렸어!
Ikki! I'm no good now!
어, 어픈딕스?
A- Appendix?
쓸 수 있겠어!
It might work!
메타비! 어픈딕스 발사 준비!
Metabee! Prepare to fire Appendix!
뭐야?
What is this?
어픈딕스 발사!
Fire Appendix!
달아나, 메타비!
Run away, Metabee!
죽는 줄 알았다...
I was almost dead...
엑스사이즈, 기능 정지.
Excise stopped functioning.
통과 열차가 들어옵니다. 통과 열차가 들어옵니다.
Passing train is incoming. Passing train is incoming.
역시 메타비 파트는 못 돌려주겠어.
You know what? I can't give you back Metabee's parts.
아, 안 돼!
S- stop it!
정말 할 거냐?
Are you really doing that?
코쿠류! 메타비 파트는 돌려받겠어!
Kokuryu! We'll take back Metabee's parts!
키쿠히메!
Kikuhime!
은혜 고맙다!
I'm indebted!
그래, 다행이야.
Yeah, what a relief!
아무래도 우리 차례는 아니었던 것 같구나.
It seems that we weren't needed here.
살아 돌아왔다!
I'm alive again!
역시 메타비는 이래야지.
This is the Metabee I know!
애초에 그리 말했잖아? 아무리 성능이 좋아도 이건 내가 아냐.
I already told you. While its performance is superior, but it's not me.
그래, 어서 돌려드리자, 메다로트 박사님께.
Yeah, let's go return this to Medarot Professor!
돌려줄 거야?
Are you giving it back?
그래. 분명 아크대시는 강해. 그래도 난 메타비가 아니면 안 돼.
Yeah. Arcdash definitely is strong, but Metabee is best for me.
그걸 확인할 수 있었다는 것만으로도 얘한테 감사해야지.
I thank this for letting me making that sure!
그런 건가...
I guess...
어쨌든, 너희들 왜 뜬금없이 여기에?
Anyway, why are you even here all of a sudden?
아니, 말하자면 긴데...
It's a long story, you know!
우연이야, 우연!
It's a luck! Just a luck!
그래도 두목, 이걸로 페퍼캣의 개조는 틀렸네요.
But boss, this means no new part for Peppercat.
뭐가 틀렸다고?
No new what?
아, 아무것도 아냐, 아무것도!
I- it's nothing! It's nothing!
어이, 잇키, 뭔가 수상해.
Hey, Ikki, they look suspicious.
뭔 소리야! 우리 스크류즈 덕분에 메타비가 살았잖아?
What are you talking about? Metabee lived thanks to us Screws!
그게 수상해.
That's what's suspicious.
그래, 수상해.
Yes, it's suspicious.
수상하지 않아, 수상하지 않아! 전혀 수상하지 않아! 페퍼캣을 메다체인지하게 하고 싶어서
Not suspicious, not suspicious! Definitely not suspicious! It's not like that I let Ginkai into Medarot Research Facility,
긴카이를 메다로트 연구소에 들인 것 말고도, 메타비 동체를 빼앗은 적 절대 없어!
and stole Metabee's body because I wanted to have my Peppercat able to perform Medachange!
야.
Hey.
미안.
Sorry.
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday on a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rings
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
As much as I'm sad, you are older than me
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun that I admire?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't make it let you down
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
긴카이의 비밀을 알게 되어 아지트에 잡힌 허니.
Honey has been taken because she found out Ginkai's secret.
잇키와 메타비는 허니를 구출하기 위해 긴카이와 싸운다.
Ikki and Metabee fight Ginkai to rescue Honey.
긴카이의 집요한 추적을 뿌리치기 위해 트럭에 올라탄 메타비와 허니.
Metabee and Honey got into a truck to shake off Ginkai's persistent pursuit.
그러나 트럭은 조종이 불가능해지고 폭주하기 시작했다.
But the truck's controls are not working, and it's about to drive recklessly.
절체절명의 메타비와 허니. 과연 그들의 운명은 어떻게?
Metabee and Honey are in desperate situation. What will happen to them?
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 허니 구출 대작전
Next time on Medarot Damashii! Operation Rescue Honey
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!